National Policy Committee Reports and Memoranda 5248
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
National Policy Committee Reports and Memoranda
1943-1945
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
National Policy Committee
5248
0.5 cubic feet
0.5 linear ft.
Memorandums, records (documents).
Reports and memoranda of the National Policy Committee.
2293760
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, June 06, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 08, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The National Policy Committee (NPC) was founded in 1935 by a group of men and women representing management, labor and the general public, who were interested in promoting discussions on the "due process of policy making which is centrally important to the democratic procedure."
The NPC organized meetings from 1935 to 1947, in various locations in the United States, in order to supply the public with information on issues of regional and national interest; to stimulate discussions of public interest in preparation for political decision making; to facilitate exchange of information; to encourage public participation in political decision making; to "ensure the translation of political thought into political action; and to work towards a national policy based on general interest rather than special interest."
Scope and Contents
Include memoranda concerning National Policy Committee dinners and reports of meetings at which were discussed political and economic issues confronting the post-war world. Include memoranda regarding NPC dinners in Washington, D.C. and New York in 1944. Matters discussed include the Dumbarton Oaks Proposal; economic controls and economic freedom; post-war international trade; manpower; price controls; surpluses, reconversion to peacetime industrial pursuits; the press and radio in wartime; the presidential election campaign; and the future of industrial risk.
Include reports of NPC sessions (1943-1945) held in Chicago, Philadelphia, Cleveland, New York, Topeka, and Billings, Mont. Topics include international civil aviation; the post-war world; world peace; Bretton Woods monetary proposals; food problems in times of war and peace; and post-war problems in education, among others.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Aeronautics, Commercial; Food supply -- Forecasting; Industrial management -- United States; Manpower policy -- United States; Draft -- United States; Presidents -- United States -- Election -- 1944; Reconstruction (1939-1951); Wage-price policy -- United States; War and emergency powers; Lobbyists; Collective labor agreements -- Mining industry -- United States; United States -- Economic policy -- 1933-1945; United States -- Economic policy -- Public opinion; National Policy Committee (U.S.)
2293760
- National Policy Memoranda, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Implications of American Transactions Abroad, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    By National Policy Committee. National Policy Memoranda no.23. Item is in English.
- National Policy Memoranda, 1944; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: The Future of Industrial Risk, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By National Policy Committee. National Policy Memoranda no.26. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Press and Radio in a Wartime Election Campaign, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By National Policy Committee. National Policy Memoranda no.27. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Surpluses, Machine Tools, Reconversion, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By National Policy Committee. National Policy Memoranda no.28. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Transition Price Controls, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By National Policy Committee. National Policy Memoranda no.30. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: The Public and The State Department, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By National Policy Committee. National Policy Memoranda no.31. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: The Public and The State Department, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By National Policy Committee. National Policy Memoranda no.31. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: Manpower From Here Out, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By National Policy Committee. National PolicyMemoranda no.32. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: Manpower From Here Out, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By National Policy Committee. National Policy Memoranda no.32. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: The Combined Approach to Postwar World Trade, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By National Policy Committee. National Policy Memoranda no.33. Item is in English.
  - Item 10: The Dumbarton Oaks Proposal, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By National Policy Committee. National Policy Memoranda no.34. Item is in English.
  - Item 11: Universal Military Training, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By National Policy Committee. National Policy Memoranda no.35. Item is in English.
  - Item 12: Universal Military Training, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By National Policy Committee. National Policy Memranda no.35. Copy 2. Item is in English.
- National Policy Memoranda, 1945; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: National Wage Policy, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By National Policy Committee. National Policy Memoranda no.36. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Economic Controls and Economic Freedom, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By National Policy Committee. National Policy Memoranda no.37. Item is in English.
- National Policy Reports, 1943; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Financial Considerations in the Postwar World; and Sovereignty and World Peace, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    By Cleveland Policy Committee. National Policy Reports no.16. Report of two sessions of the Cleveland Policy Committee, Cleveland, OH, March 20 and April 24, 1943. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Inter-American Progress and Problems, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    By National Policy Committee. National Policy Reports no.17. Report of an Institute sponsored by Topeka Chamber of Commerce, Washburn Municipal University, Kansas State Teachers' Association, Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs, and Western Policy Committee. Topeka, Kansas, June 14-15, 1943. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Postwar Employment in Arkansas, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    By Arkansas Policy Committee. National Policy Reports no.18. Report of the Arkansas Policy Committee. Little Rock, AR, August 31, 1943. Item is in English.
- National Policy Reports, 1944; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: What Effect Will the End of the War with Gerrmany Have on Philadelphia, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    By The Philadelphia Group. National Policy Reports no.21. Report of the Philadelphia Group. Philadelphia, PA, January 5, 1944. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Postwar Problems in Education, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    By The Philadelphia Group. National Policy Reports no.22. Report of two sessions of the Philadelphia Group. Philadelphia, PA, Feruary 14 and March 13, 1944. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: What War-Time Patterns of Government Should Continue Into Peace?; and Unions, Management, and Government After the War, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    By National Policy Committee. National Policy Reports no.23. Reports of sessions in Philadelphia and Cleveland. Philadelphia, PA, April 13, 1944 and Cleveland, OH, May 20, 1944. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: American Economic Interests in the Far East, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    By The Philadelphia Group. National Policy Reports no.24. Report of a session of the Philadelphia Group, Philadelphia, PA, May 23, 1944. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Food Problems in War and Peace, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    By National Policy Committee. National Policy Reports no.25. Report of a session in Des Mines, IA. Des Moines, IA, July 18, 1944. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: World Organization as Proposed at Dumbarton Oaks, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    By National Policy Committee. National Policy Reports no.26. Reports of sessions in Cleveland, Philadelphia, and Arkansas. Cleveland, OH, October 14, 1944; Philadelphia, PA, November 10, 1944; Little Rock, AR, December 2, 1944. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: The Bretton Woods Monetary Proposals, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    By Cleveland Policy Committee. National Policy Reports no.27. Based on two sessions of the Cleveland Policy Committee. Cleveland, OH, November 25, 1944 and January 13, 1945. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: Upper Missouri River Development, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    By National Policy Committee. National Policy Reports no.28. Report of a session in Billings, MT. Billings, MT, December 1-2, 1944. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: Upper Missouri River Development, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    By National Policy Committee. Natonal Policy Reports no.28. Report of a session in Billings, MT. Billings, MT, December 1-2, 1944. Copy 2. Item is in English.
- National Policy Reports, 1945; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: International Civil Aviation, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    By National Policy Committee. National Policy Reports no.29. Report of a session in Chicago, IL, March 15, 1945. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: International Civil Aviation, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    By National Policy Committee. National Policy Reports no.29. Report of a session in Chicago, IL, March 15, 1945. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: The Citizen and City Hall; and Strengthening the Congress, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    By National Policy Committee. National Policy Reports no.30. Reports of sessions in Philadelphia and Cleveland. Philadelphia, PA, March 13, 1945 and Cleveland, OH, February 17, 1945. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: The Citizen and City Hall; and Strengthening the Congress, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    By National Policy Committee. National Policy Reports no.30. Reports of sessions in Philadelphia and Cleveland. Philadelphia, PA, March 13, 1945 and Cleveland, OH, February 17, 1945. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Those 60,000,000 Postwar Jobs, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    By Cleveland Policy Committee. National Policy Reports no.31. Report of a session of the Cleveland Policy Committee. Cleveland, OH, March 31, 1945. Item is in English.